<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Chen</title>
    <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Athul</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 18:54:38 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.chenaciousD.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curiosity is all you need: How GenAI will transform creativity</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/genaiperpsective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 18:54:38 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/genaiperpsective/</guid>
      <description>Anyone can create GenAI dramatically reduces the barriers to creativity. I&amp;rsquo;m not referring solely to creativity within professional fields like design and art, although it will undoubtedly have a substantial impact there as well. What I mean is creativity in its broadest sense—the act of envisioning and bringing an idea to life, your own idea, independently.
Curiosity is all you need For me, GPT has sparked a new enthusiasm and energy for learning and creation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three ways I played with OpenAI&#39;s APIs</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/threewaysllms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/threewaysllms/</guid>
      <description>My motiviation behind these experiments I was curious about the hype around GenAI so I wanted to play with the technology firsthand. Here are a few examples of what I created. Each of these applications was built with the assistance of GPT or Github Co-Pilot.
Learn that Law: An Example of Retrieval Augmentation Generation My first project was to build a simple RAG which is the basis of many LLM use cases that enable users to query an external data source with natural language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiments in supervised and reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/learningexperiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/learningexperiments/</guid>
      <description>My motivation behind these experiments After reading the Alignment Problem and taking a deep learning class from fast.ai. I was interested in learning how some of the learning methods worked in practice.
Training my own Neural Net My goal was to see an end-to-end machine learning workflow. I used the FastAI library for its ease of use. I found a dataset available from Harvard. The Annotated Image Database of Architecture is comprised of about 15,000 images that are pre-labeled across various categories including building type and location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some of my observations and reflections on being a PM</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/pmlearnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 18:54:38 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/pmlearnings/</guid>
      <description>The following are some reflections and principles that I have taken away from my time being a product manager at a scaling startup.
Create the spectre of Mutually Assured Inspiration 💡 Everyone in R&amp;amp;D must have enough context about the business, the customer and the technology. This trifecta of knowledge forms the Context Triad, which is essential for fostering Mutually Assured Inspiration. A silo&amp;rsquo;d team where engineers only know the tech, the designer knows the customer and the product person knows the business is not only bad for the business, it&amp;rsquo;s not a fun way to collaborate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding more light and spatial variety to a historic loft</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/clocktower/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/clocktower/</guid>
      <description>Loft view Collaboration During COVID, I collaborated with Hesselbrand to renovate my loft. Because the architect was based in London and Oslo, we used several techniques including 3D scans and models to communicate the design intent. As part of the Hesselbrand team, I led the permitting and execution of this project.
Context The Clocktower Building, located in the South Beach neighbourhood of San Francisco, is one of the city&amp;rsquo;s iconic landmarks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 12:13:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Professional Experience Group Product Manager - Juniper Square (2020 - 2023)
Juniper Square is a Series C fintech startup with $100 mil+ in funding. It combines a CRM, investor portal and investor reporting into a unified platform for fund managers. I was responsible for the IR reporting product during a period of rapid scaling (5x revenue and 5x in employees). Initiatives that I led include our expansion into private equity and venture capital, our overall enterprise strategy and roadmap and our approach to integrations and APIs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical: In search of dysutopia</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/dyustopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/dyustopia/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, I took a 2 month inspiration trip, traveling through Europe to investigate failed utopias and bicycles. The following was my itinerary:
What is Dysutopia?
Helsinki, Finland Tapiola Helsinki waterfront Berlin, Hamburg, Germany Kleingartens in Berlin IBA Hamburg Intentional Communities Interbau Berlin Berlin Baugruppen Frizz23 Kreuzberg Amsterdam, Rotterdam, Netherlands Dutch design Rotterdam Utrecht cycling parking garage Schoonschip London, Milton Keynes, UK The Barbican Milton Keynes Barcelona, Spain Walden 7 Tactical Urbanism - Barcelona Superblock Malmo, Sweden Bo01 Ohboy Malmo (cycling hotel) Copenhagen, Denmark Orestad District others </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation for a Major Energy Utility</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/energy/</guid>
      <description>Design Language System The Ask In 2017 one of Australia’s leading energy utilities approached frog to partner on a major digital transformation. With a clear mandate to improve customer experience and retention, frog’s engagement included in-depth customer research, concepting, business case validation, foundational design, and a clear roadmap and process for implementation.
The Process The frog team was comprised of interaction designers, visual designers, strategists, and software architects collaborating on multiple streams of work to ensure balanced perspectives from design, business, and technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Ordering App for Robotic Hambuger Maker</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/creator/</guid>
      <description>Landing Page The Ask Creator, an SF-based startup attempting to disrupt the industrialized food system, asked frog to design a mobile ordering and burger customization app that showcased its revolutionary machine. (Note: The machine itself was designed by noted automotive designer, Per Selvaag).
The Process The frog team was comprised of interaction designers, visual designers and strategists who collaborated to design the MVP version of Creator’s mobile ordering app. My role on the team included:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brand and Personality Design for an AI Financial Chatbot</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/charlie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/charlie/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Homepage The Ask Charlie Finance (since acquired by Chime), a fintech startup approached frog to help integrate product, brand, and marketing for a financial assistant chatbot that users interacted exclusively over text.
The Process The frog team was comprised of interaction designers, visual designers, and copywriters. My role included:
Brand strategy, character and product bible and origin story Contribute to interaction model conceptualization and on-boarding design Marketing and storytelling narrative for landing page Facilitation of key client alignment and reviews Engagement scoping, planning, contracting, and frogVentures investment documentation Integrating Product, Brand &amp;amp; Marketing for a Cohesive Experience During our brand/character discovery phase, the team looked to several areas of inspiration - from animals to robots to abstract chat bubbles:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customer Experience Design for AT&amp;T</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/att/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/att/</guid>
      <description>Animated Short for Board of Directors The Ask A leading US telco asked frog to envision the company’s future end to end customer experience. The telco had recently acquired new media/content assets that increased its competitive advantage, enabling it to offer a richer suite of products and content to customers.
The Process The frog team was comprised of interaction designers, visual designers, and strategists. My role on the team included:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Personality Car for Leading Japanese Automaker</title>
      <link>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/toyota/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.chenaciousD.com/projects/toyota/</guid>
      <description>Movie Poster Inspiration for Car-Driver Relationship The Ask In 2016, a leading Japanese automaker engaged frog to envision an AI concept car of the future by reconceptualizing the relationship between car and driver and leveraging emerging technologies such as AI, autonomous driving and new digital interfaces.
The Process The frog team was comprised of interaction designers, visual designers, film/motion animators, mechanical engineers, strategists and industrial designers. My role on the team included:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
